Guide to the Henry Adams La Farge Papers Relating to a Catalogue Raisonné of Works by John La Farge
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Henry Adams La Farge papers relating to a catalogue raisonné of works by John La Farge
1965-1998
YCAL MSS 653
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
25.39
(47 boxes)
The collection consists of material created and accumulated by Henry Adams La Farge and others in the course of researching and compiling an unpublished catalogue raisonné of works by the American artist John La Farge. Material includes descriptive text and photographic reproductions of La Farge's works in various media, including oil paintings, drawings, watercolors, glass, and engravings; extensive correspondence files relating to the provenance of works by La Farge; and research and other files consisting of lists, catalogs, slides, photographs, correspondence, notes and other material. The collection documents the scope, history, and provenance of works of art by John La Farge, as well as the process of producing a catalogue raisonné.
La Farge, Henry Adams, 1902-
La Farge, John, 1835-1910
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Bam La Farge, 2003.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
La Farge Family Papers (MS 24). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Henry Adams La Farge (1902-1985)
Henry Adams La Farge (1902-1985), grandson of the American artist John La Farge, was an art administrator, historian, and editor. He edited the book Lost Treasures of Europe: 427 Photographs (1946) and compiled a catalogue raisonné of works by John La Farge that was never published.
John La Farge (1835-1910)
John La Farge (1835-1910), American painter, muralist, stained-glass designer, and writer.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of material created and accumulated by Henry Adams La Farge and others in the course of researching and compiling an unpublished catalogue raisonné of works by the American artist John La Farge. Material includes descriptive text and photographic reproductions of La Farge's works in various media, including oil paintings, drawings, watercolors, glass, and engravings; extensive correspondence files relating to the provenance of works by La Farge; and research and other files consisting of lists, catalogs, slides, photographs, correspondence, notes and other material. The collection documents the scope, history, and provenance of works of art by John La Farge, as well as the process of producing a catalogue raisonné.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. John La Farge Catalogue Raisonné Material. II. Sale, Provenance, and Research Material. III. Provenance Correspondence. IV. Other Research and Correspondence Files.
Art -- Catalogs; Art, American -- 19th century; Art, Modern -- 19th century -- History; Art -- Provenance; Artists -- United States; Catalogues raisonnés; Photographic prints; Slides (photographs); Artists -- United States -- 19th century; La Farge, Henry Adams, 1902-; La Farge, John, 1835-1910; La Farge, John, 1835-1910 -- Catalogues raisonnés
- John La Farge Catalogue Raisonné Material, Series I; 9.42; (9 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized under the following headings: Oil Paintings, Drawings, Watercolors, Decorative Watercolors, Glass, Engravings, and Miscellaneous Decoration.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of descriptive text and photographic reproductions of La Farge's works in various media, including oil paintings, drawings, watercolors, glass, and engraving. The numbering schemes for works in various media are those devised by the creator.
  - Oil Paintings
    - Current text, 1998; 3 (Box 1)
    - Images
      - P010-P060: Photographs, self-portraits, landscapes, 2 (Box 1)
      - P070-P100: Photographs, still lifes, other still lifes, portraits, studio portraits, 2 (Box 1)
      - P110-P210: Photographs, literary, mythological, religious figures, Japan and South Seas PH 010, 2 (Box 1)
  - Drawings
    - 1841-55, 2 (Box 1)
    - 1856-57, 2 (Box 1)
    - 1857-60 I, 2 (Box 1)
    - 1860 II, 2 (Box 2)
    - 1860 III (Box 2)
    - 1861-62, 2 (Box 2)
    - 1863 I, 2 (Box 2)
    - 1863 II, 2 (Box 2)
    - 1863 III, 2 (Box 2)
    - 1864, 2 (Box 2)
    - 1865 I, 2 (Box 2)
    - 1865 II (Box 3)
    - 1865 III, 4 (Box 3)
    - 1866 I, 2 (Box 3)
    - 1866 II, 2 (Box 3)
    - 1866 III, 2 (Box 3)
    - 1866-67, 2 (Box 3)
    - 1867 II (Box 3)
    - 1867-68, 3 (Box 3)
    - 1869-72, 2 (Box 4)
    - 1872-75, 2 (Box 4)
    - 1876, 2 (Box 4)
    - 1876-79, 2 (Box 4)
    - 1880-82, 2 (Box 4)
    - 1883-86, 2 (Box 4)
    - 1886-90, 2 (Box 4)
    - 1890-91, 2 (Box 4)
    - 1891-98, 2 (Box 5)
    - 1899-1900, 2 (Box 5)
    - 1901-09, 2 (Box 5)
    - Drawings: D1883.102-D1883.191 (La Farge Decorative Art Company), 3 (Box 5)
  - Watercolors
    - Text 010-260, 3 (Box 5)
    - Images
      - W010-W080, 2 (Box 5)
      - W090-W160, 2 (Box 6)
      - W170-W180, 2 (Box 6)
      - W190-W200, 2 (Box 6)
      - W210-W260, 3 (Box 6)
  - Decorative Watercolors
    - W1874-W1882, 3 (Box 6)
    - W1883.1-W1883.110, 2 (Box 6)
    - W1883.111-W1883 end, 3 (Box 7)
    - W1884-W1886, 2 (Box 7)
    - W1887-W1890, 3 (Box 7)
    - W1891-W1896, 2 (Box 7)
    - W1897-W1900, 2 (Box 7)
    - W1901-W1910, 3 (Box 8)
  - Glass
    - 1874-1880, 3 (Box 8)
    - 1881.1-1881.24 (Box 8)
    - 1881.25-1881.88, 2 (Box 8)
    - 1882.1-1882.13 (Box 8)
    - 1882.14-1883.12 (Box 8)
    - 1883.13-1884.13, 2 (Box 8)
    - 1885-1887, 2 (Box 8)
    - 1888-1889, 2 (Box 9)
    - 1890-1894, 2 (Box 9)
    - 1895-1897, 2 (Box 9)
    - 1898-1901, 2 (Box 9)
    - 1902-1904 (Box 9)
    - 1905-1910, 2 (Box 9)
  - Engravings
    - Current text, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Engravings photographs, 2 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Decoration
    - Current text, 1998; 3 (Box 9)
    - Images
      - MD010-MD020 photographs: King tomb and ecclesiastical, 2 (Box 10)
      - MD030-MD050 photographs: domestic, embroidery, and civic, 2 (Box 10)
- Sale, Provenance and Research Material, Series II; 2; (2 boxes)
  - Title list and report, references, catalogue, 2 (Box 11)
  - Exhibitions, and references, abbreviated, 3 (Box 11)
  - Sample pages from the catalogue raisonne of works by John La Farge (1835-1910). Paintings, watercolors, and glass, 2 (Box 11)
  - Pages from the catalogue raisonne of stained glass by John La Farge with extended commentaries on each work (Box 11)
  - Number, source, owner cross-references (Box 11)
  - Drawing, etching, miscellaneous decorative, and stained glass cross-references (Box 11)
  - Watercolor cross-references, rejected and doubtful, 2 (Box 11)
  - McNally works catalogue, 2 (Box 11)
  - Not sale/rejects
    - Miscellaneous decoration retired text 1974-98, 3 (Box 12)
    - Oil painting retired text 1974-98, 3 (Box 12)
    - Engravings retired text 1974-98, 2 (Box 12)
    - Glass rejects/doubtful/unresolved, 5 (Box 12)
    - Oil painting rejects/doubtful/unresolved (Box 12)
- Provenance Correspondence, Series III; 9.18; (23 boxes)
  Organized under two headings and then alphabetically by name or subject: Stained Glass; and Paintings, Drawings, Engravings, Miscellaneous Decoration, Watercolors
  - Stained Glass
    - Aurora, New York- Wells College (Box 13)
    - Armstrong, Helen Maitland (Box 13)
    - Baltimore, Maryland (Box 13)
      - Emmanuel Church (Box 13)
      - Jenkins (Box 13)
      - Mount Calvary Episcopal Church (Box 13)
      - Roland Park (Box 13)
      - Old Saint Paul's (Box 13)
      - Saint Peter's Cathedral (Box 13)
    - Beverly Farms, Massachusetts- Adams (Box 13)
    - Boston, Massachusetts (Box 13)
      - Summary of works (Box 13)
      - Ames (Box 13)
      - Gardner (Box 13)
      - Mount Vernon (Box 13)
      - Proctor (Box 13)
      - Roxbury, All Saints Unitarian (Box 13)
      - Trinity Church (Box 13)
      - Whittier house (Box 13)
    - Bowen house (Box 13)
    - Buffalo, New York- Kowsky (Box 13)
    - Brookline, Massachusetts- Storrow house- Richardson (Box 13)
    - Canton, New York- Grover (Box 13)
    - Calvary Cemetery (Box 13)
    - Cambridge, Massachusetts- Mason memorial windows (Box 13)
    - Cambridge, Massachusetts- Memorial Hall (Box 13)
    - Chicago, Illinois- Board of Trade, etc. (Box 13)
    - Chicago churches (Box 14)
    - Christie's (Box 14)
    - Cleveland, Ohio (Box 14)
    - Colorado Springs- Pettigrew Auction Company (Box 14)
    - Connick, Charles J., Associates (Box 14)
    - Columbia, Missouri (Box 14)
    - Corning Museum (Box 14)
    - Croul, Robert Elwood (antiques) (Box 14)
    - Cummings (Box 14)
    - Derby window (Box 14)
    - Detroit, Michigan (Box 14)
    - Easport, Maine (Box 14)
    - Elberon, New Jersey- Newcomb house (Box 14)
    - Elmsford, New York- Saint Joseph of Arimathea Church (Box 14)
    - Englewood, New Jersey- Ophir gallery (Box 14)
    - Garrison, Maryland (Box 14)
    - Geneseo, New York (Box 14)
    - Hammondsport, New York (Remaily) (Box 14)
    - Heinigke (Box 14)
    - Humbert window (Box 14)
    - Jamaica Plain, Massachusetts- Charles Tennant Lee (Box 14)
    - Jenkintown, Pennsylvania- Episcopal Church of Our Savior (Box 14)
    - Kansas City, Missouri (Box 14)
    - Kundhardt (Box 14)
    - La Farge- patent, etc. (Box 14)
    - Lake Mohegan (Box 14)
    - Lamb (Box 14)
    - Litchfield, Connecticut (Box 15)
    - London, England- Southwark cathedral (Box 15)
    - Lonsdale, Rhode Island- Christ Church (Box 15)
    - Magnolia, Massachusetts- Longfellow (Box 15)
    - Mamaroneck, New York- Osborn house (Box 15)
    - Manchester, Massachusetts- Emmanuel Church (Box 15)
    - McKim (Mead and White) (commissions and records) (Box 15)
    - McNally (Box 15)
    - McPherson/ McDonald (Box 15)
    - Medford, Massachusetts (Box 15)
    - Methuen Memorial Music Hall (Box 15)
    - Minneapolis- Saint Paul (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 (Box 15)
    - Munich, Germany (Box 15)
    - Natchez, Mississippi (Box 15)
    - New Haven, Connecticut (Box 15)
    - Newport, Rhode Island (Box 15)
      - C. C. Baldwin (Box 15)
      - Congregational Church (Box 15)
      - Caldwell house (Box 16)
      - Channing Memorial Church (Box 16)
    - Newton, Massachusetts- Grace Church (Box 16)
    - New York City (Box 16)
      - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters (Box 16)
      - Bloomingdale Church (Box 16)
      - Bowen house (Box 16)
      - Brooklyn dawn window (Box 16)
      - Church of the Ascension (Box 16)
      - Church of Saint Paul the Apostle (Box 16)
      - Columbia University Saint Paul Chapel (Box 16)
      - Hotel Normandy (Box 16)
      - Humbert window (Box 16)
      - Judson (Box 16)
      - Marquand (Box 16)
      - Maxwell's Plum (Box 16)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Bliss window) (Box 16)
      - Mills window (now in Osaka, Japan) (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
      - Morgan, J. P. (Box 16)
      - The National Arts Club (Box 16)
      - Osborne (Box 16)
      - St. James' Church (Box 16)
      - Vanderbilt (Cornelius) house (Box 16)
      - Villard- Reid (Box 16)
      - Whitney (Box 16)
      - Worsham (Box 16)
      - Zerega (Box 16)
    - Norfolk, Virginia (Box 17)
    - North Easton, Massachusetts, 2 (Box 17)
    - Onteora (Box 17)
    - Peekskill, New York (Box 17)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Box 17)
    - Photopulas, Susan (Box 17)
    - Pittsburg, Pennsylvania- Frick building (Box 17)
    - Pleasant Valley, New York (auction) (Box 17)
    - Princeton- Marquand Chapel (Box 17)
    - Providence, Rhode Island (Box 17)
      - Cathedral of St. John (Box 17)
      - Church of the Blessed Sacrament (Box 17)
      - Goddard House (Box 17)
    - Quincy, Massachusetts (Box 17)
    - Rambusch (Box 17)
    - Rock Island, Illinois (Box 17)
    - Salem, Massachusetts (Box 17)
    - Sotheby's (Box 17)
    - Sewickley- First Presbyterian Church (Box 17)
    - Southhampton, Massachusetts (Box 17)
    - Springfield, Massachusetts (Box 17)
    - Stockbridge, Massachusetts (Box 17)
    - St. James Episcopal Church (Box 17)
    - St. Louis, Missouri (Box 18)
    - St. Paul- Hill (Box 18)
    - St. Petersburg, Florida (Box 18)
    - Strum and Staten Island, New York (Box 18)
    - Taos, New Mexico- Singer, Larry (Box 18)
    - Tiffany (Box 18)
    - Troy, New York (Box 18)
    - Tuxedo Park, New York (Box 18)
    - Vassar Chapel (Box 18)
    - Vareika, William (Box 18)
    - Washington, D.C. (Box 18)
      - Anderson house (Box 18)
      - National Collection of Fine Arts (Box 18)
      - Wadsworth (Herbert) house (Box 18)
      - Yullee house (Box 18)
    - Wellesley College (Box 18)
    - Wellesley, Massachusetts- Hunnewell (Box 18)
    - West Orange, New Jersey- Pedder-Edison house (Box 18)
    - Williamstown, Massachusetts (Box 18)
    - Woodlawn cemetery- Lorillard (Box 18)
    - Winter Park, Florida (Box 18)
    - Worcester, Massachusetts (Box 18)
    - Montclair, New Jersey- Thomas Wright house (Box 19)
    - Garretts of Baltimore (Box 19)
    - Brooklyn, New York- Christ Church and Holy Family etc. (Box 19)
    - Columbia, Kansas- Calvary Episcopal Church (Box 19)
    - Baltimore- Mallory (Box 19)
    - Hartford, Connecticut- Phelps house (Box 19)
    - Middletown, Rhode Island- St. Columba's Church (Box 19)
    - Newport, Rhode Island- Watts and Sherman (Box 19)
    - New York City- Fourth Presbyterian Church (Annunciation Greek Orthodox Church) (Box 19)
    - Peace Dale, Rhode Island (Box 19)
    - Pomfret, Connecticut (Box 19)
    - Rochester, New York (Box 20)
    - Staten Island, New York- Sailors' Snug Harbor Chapel (Box 20)
    - Rejected attributions (Box 20)
  - Paintings, Drawings, Engravings, Miscellaneous Decoration, Watercolors
    - Accessories (Box 21)
    - Ackerman, Paul H. (Box 21)
    - Adams, Henry (Box 21)
    - Addison Gallery (Box 21)
    - Adleson, Warren (Box 21)
    - Agassiz (Box 21)
    - Albright, Charlotte and Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 21)
    - Allen, Lewis (Box 21)
    - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters/ National Institute of Arts and Letters (Box 21)
    - American Art & Antiques (Box 21)
    - American Art Association/ American Art Galleries, Anderson Galleries, etc. (Box 21)
    - American Art Search (Box 21)
    - American Museum of Natural History (Box 21)
    - Ames, J. B. and Mrs. Robert (Box 21)
    - Ames, Winslow (Box 21)
    - Amherst College (Box 21)
    - Amon Carter Museum (Box 21)
    - Amory, Walter (Box 21)
    - Anderson, Lee and Harriet (Box 21)
    - Antiquarian Antiques (Box 21)
    - Appellate Court New York City (Box 21)
    - Architectural Record (Box 21)
    - Archives of American Art (Box 21)
    - Arnot Art Museum (Box 21)
    - The Art Institute of Chicago (Box 21)
    - Art Research of Cambridge (Box 21)
    - The Arts Group (Box 21)
    - Ash, William (Box 21)
    - Ashton, David G. (Box 21)
    - Atlass (Box 21)
    - Ayer (Box 21)
    - Babcock Galleries, Inc. (Box 21)
    - Baine, Michael (Box 21)
    - Baker, Jill (Box 21)
    - Bakker, James R. (Box 21)
    - Balfour, Anne and Buxton, Eva (Box 21)
    - Ball State University (Box 21)
    - The Baltimore Museum of Art (Box 21)
    - Bancroft family and Blackie, Pauline (Box 21)
    - Bangs (Box 21)
    - Barnes, Grace (Box 21)
    - The Barnacle Gallery (Box 21)
    - Barridoff Galleries (Box 21)
    - Bartholet, Elizabeth Ives (Box 21)
    - Barwick, Thomas W. (Box 21)
    - Bass, Rosie (Box 21)
    - Batchelder, Mimi (Box 22)
    - Bauer, Melanie L. (Box 22)
    - Beard, Anson, Jr. (Box 22)
    - Bennedict- Greenwich, Connecticut (Box 22)
    - Bender, William H., Jr. (Box 22)
    - Bentley, Fred D., Sr. (Box 22)
    - The William Benton Museum of Art (Box 22)
    - Berea College (Box 22)
    - Bereczki, Csaba (Box 22)
    - Berger-Hughes, Mary Lee (Box 22)
    - The Berkshire Museum (Box 22)
    - Berridge, J. W. (Box 22)
    - Berry-Hill Galleries, Inc. (Box 22)
    - Biddle (Irving), Flora Miller (Box 22)
    - Binsse (Box 22)
    - Bienenstock, Jennifer A. (Box 22)
    - Bigelow (Box 22)
    - Birmingham Museum (Box 22)
    - Bishop, Jonathan S. (Box 22)
    - Bishop Museum (Box 22)
    - Bixby, Ralph F. (Box 22)
    - Blake, Rosemary S. (Box 22)
    - Blankenship, Roy and Insley, Albert (Box 22)
    - Bloch, E. Maurice (Box 22)
    - Booth, Mrs. Philips Dodge (Box 22)
    - Booton, Mrs. John Griffin (Box 22)
    - Museum of Fine Arts Boston (Box 22)
    - Museum of Fine Arts Boston, photographs (Box 22)
    - Boston Public Library (Box 23)
    - Richard A. Bourne Co., INC. (Box 23)
    - Bowdoin College (Box 23)
    - Boyle, Richard J. (Box 23)
    - Bradley family (Box 23)
    - Bridgeport Museum of Art, Science & Industry (Box 23)
    - Brigham Young University (Box 23)
    - The Brooklyn Museum (Box 23)
    - Brooks, Alfred (Box 23)
    - Brown Jeffrey and Corbin, James (Box 23)
    - Brown, Mrs. Slater (Box 23)
    - Büek [?] (Box 23)
    - Buffalo State University Lecture and Kowsky, Francis (Box 23)
    - Bundy, Mrs. Harvey (Box 23)
    - Burchard, Peter (Box 23)
    - Burke, Russell (Box 23)
    - Burstein, Barney (Box 23)
    - Bush Galleries (Box 23)
    - The Butler Institute of American Art (Box 23)
    - Butterfield & Butterfield (Box 23)
    - Byers, Frank (Box 23)
    - Cabot family (Box 23)
    - Calan, Comtesse Phillippe de (Box 23)
    - Cameron, Elizabeth Sherman (Box 23)
    - Campbell, Robert (Box 23)
    - Canajoharte Library and Art Gallery (Box 23)
    - Carbonneau, Gay (Box 23)
    - Carmine, Al (Box 23)
    - The Carnegie Museum of Art (Box 23)
    - Carpenter, Editha (Box 23)
    - Carrell, Mr. and Mrs. Richard (Box 23)
    - Carrell, Mr. and Mrs. Joseph (Box 23)
    - Castano Gallery (Box 23)
    - Cecil, M. A. (Box 23)
    - The Century Association (Box 23)
    - Chandler, Ashley [?] and William (Box 23)
    - Chester family (Box 23)
    - Chevalley, Mrs. S. (Box 23)
    - Chicago Historical Society (Box 23)
    - Childs Gallery (Box 23)
    - Christie's (Box 23)
    - The Chrysler Museum (Box 23)
    - Church of the Ascension (Box 24)
    - Church of the Incarnation (Box 24)
    - Churchill, Jonathan H. (Box 24)
    - Ciccarelli, Anthony J. (Box 24)
    - Cincinnati Art Museum (Box 24)
    - Clark Art Institute (Box 24)
    - Clark, Stephen C. (Box 24)
    - Clark, Willard G. (Box 24)
    - Clarke, Peter J. (Box 24)
    - Claxton family (Box 24)
    - Clements, Geoffrey (Box 24)
    - The Cleveland Museum of Art (Box 24)
    - Coe Kerr Gallery Inc. (Box 24)
    - Cogswell, Mrs. Edward R. (Box 24)
    - Calacino, Jana T. (Box 24)
    - Coll, Ione L. (Box 24)
    - Colt, Charles C. (Box 24)
    - Columbia University (Box 24)
    - Columbus Museum of Art (Box 24)
    - Colville, Thomas (Box 24)
    - Comenos Gallery (Box 24)
    - Connolly, Florence (Box 24)
    - The Cooley Gallery (Box 24)
    - Coolidge family (Box 24)
    - Cooper-Hewitt Museum of Design (Box 24)
    - The Corcoran Gallery of Art (Box 24)
    - Cotting, Charles E. (Box 24)
    - Croker, Louise M. (Box 24)
    - Culleton, Dale (Box 24)
    - Cunningham, Mrs. Alan (Box 24)
    - Curtis family (Box 24)
    - The Currier Gallery of Art (Box 24)
    - Cushing, Mr. and Mrs. Howard G. (Box 24)
    - Cutler, Roger (Box 24)
    - Cuyler, Lewis B. (Box 24)
    - D'Agostino, Judith A. (Box 24)
    - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts (Box 24)
    - Danes, Gibson A. (Box 24)
    - Daniels, David (Box 24)
    - Danneman, Mr. and Mrs. (Box 24)
    - Darby-Barrett Fine Antiques and Paintings (Box 24)
    - Dartmouth College Library (Box 24)
    - Davidson, Peter H. (Box 24)
    - Davis, Greta Erickson (Box 24)
    - Davis & Langdale Company, Inc. (Box 24)
    - Davison, John (Box 24)
    - Davol, Mrs. George (Box 24)
    - Day, Howard D. (Box 24)
    - Dayton Avenue Presbyterian Church (Box 24)
    - Dear, Mr. and Mrs. William Y. (Box 24)
    - Dentzel, Carl and Waldo-Dentzel, Elizabeth (Box 24)
    - The Detroit Institute of Arts (Box 24)
    - Detroit Publishing Co. and The State Historical Society of Colorado (Box 24)
    - Dexter family (Box 24)
    - Dillenberger, John and Jane (Box 24)
    - Dinnerstein, Lois (Box 24)
    - Dodd Wilkinson, Sandra [?] (Box 24)
    - Doll & Richards Fine Arts (Box 24)
    - Dordet, Matilda S. (Box 24)
    - Dorrie, Marea K. (Box 24)
    - Downer, George A. (Box 25)
    - William Doyle Galleries (Box 25)
    - Dreier, Dorothea A. (Box 25)
    - Durand-Ruel & Cie. (Box 25)
    - Duveneck, Josephine W. (Box 25)
    - DuVivier family (Box 25)
    - Dwight, Ronald A. (Box 25)
    - Edgeworth, Richard (Box 25)
    - Edinburgh, Scotland- National Gallery of Scotland (Box 25)
    - Elliot, Mrs. John M. (Box 25)
    - Engel, Michael (Box 25)
    - Emmet, Mr. and Mrs. Richard S. (Box 25)
    - John Espo Colonial Antiques (Box 25)
    - Everson Museum of Art (Box 25)
    - Fairchild [?] (Box 25)
    - Fano, Enzo (Box 25)
    - Farnsworth Museum (Box 25)
    - Farrand, Beatrix (Box 25)
    - Fay, Gertrude S. (Box 25)
    - Fazio, Peter V. (Box 25)
    - Ferguson, Francis H. (Box 25)
    - Ffolliott, Gertrude B. (Box 25)
    - Filides, Michael (Box 25)
    - Fillin, Walter and Lucille (Box 25)
    - Fischer, Diane P. (Box 25)
    - Fitch, Priscilla Hall (Box 25)
    - Fogg Art Museum (Box 25)
    - Folk, Thomas (Box 25)
    - Forbes, William H. (Box 25)
    - Ford, Daniel B. (Box 25)
    - Forsyth, Mr. and Mrs. William H. (Box 25)
    - Foster, Kathleen A. (Box 25)
    - Fowler, Jacqueline (Box 25)
    - Fraad, Daniel (Box 25)
    - Francis, Harry (Box 25)
    - Frank, Ruth D. (Box 25)
    - Frazee, Gloria (Box 25)
    - Frick Art Reference Library (Box 25)
    - Friedsam Memorial Library (Box 25)
    - Friend, George M. (Box 25)
    - Fukushima (Box 25)
    - Galerie Mongeon (Box 25)
    - Ganz, Julian, Jr. (Box 25)
    - Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum (Box 25)
    - Garmy, Louise B. (Box 25)
    - Garvan Coyle, Marcia (Box 25)
    - Georgia Museum of Art (Box 25)
    - Gerdht, William H. (Box 25)
    - The Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities (Box 25)
    - Gibson, Bob (Box 25)
    - Gilder, Rosamond (Box 25)
    - Glen Cove (Box 25)
    - Glen Cove Public Library (Box 26)
    - Goddard, Hope [?] (Box 26)
    - Goelet, Robert, residence (Box 26)
    - Goldman, Irving (Box 26)
    - Gordon, Douglas and Harriet (Box 26)
    - Goodyear, Frank H., Jr. (Box 26)
    - Goring, Al (Box 26)
    - Graham Gallery (Box 26)
    - Granados, Michael H. (Box 26)
    - Groves, W. E. (Box 26)
    - Grubman, Caroline M. (Box 26)
    - Guggenheim, Barbara (Box 26)
    - Hague, Bill (Box 26)
    - Hale, Mrs. Robert B. (Box 26)
    - Hall family (Box 26)
    - Ham, Mrs. Thomas Hale (Box 26)
    - Hamil family (Box 26)
    - Hamilton Gallery (Box 26)
    - Harris, Rich (Box 26)
    - Harrison, Gilbert A. (Box 26)
    - Harty, Agnes S. (Box 26)
    - Harvard University (Box 26)
    - Hatch, John Davis (Box 26)
    - Haupt, Enid A. (Box 26)
    - Haverstick, Iola S. (Box 26)
    - Hay, Clarence and Alice (Box 26)
    - Hazard, Jeffrey (Box 26)
    - P. A. Hearst Museum of Anthropology (Box 26)
    - Hebard, Morgan, Jr. (Box 26)
    - Hecht, Robert (Box 26)
    - Hecker, Isaac (Box 26)
    - Hecker, Neva (Box 26)
    - Heins & La Farge (Box 26)
    - Hewitt, Agnes (Box 26)
    - Hickory Ledge Gallery (Box 26)
    - Higginson, Mrs. Alexander Henry (Box 26)
    - Hill, James J. (Box 26)
    - Hill-Stead Museum (Box 26)
    - Hirschl and Adler Galleries (Box 26)
    - Hispanic Society (Box 26)
    - Hitt, Merritt S. (Box 26)
    - Hobbs, Susan (Box 26)
    - Hoffman, F. Burrall and Dolly (Box 26)
    - Hollister, Harriet Sturgis (Box 26)
    - Holmes, Virgil L., Jr. (Box 26)
    - Holt, Henry B. (Box 26)
    - Homans family (Box 26)
    - Homer, Charles L. (Box 26)
    - Honolulu Academy of Arts (Box 26)
    - Hooper, Edward (and Hirshler) (Box 27)
    - Horioka, Mr. and Mrs. Yasuko- Kwannon (Box 27)
    - Horowitz, Raymond and Fran (Box 27)
    - Horsey, Outerbridge and Helen (Box 27)
    - Houghton (Box 27)